<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-18T13:57:06-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Clowder Framework</title><subtitle>Open Source Data Management for Long Tail Data</subtitle><author><name>Clowder Framework</name></author><entry><title type="html">v1.8.3 Released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/28/v1.8.3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="v1.8.3 Released" /><published>2020-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/28/v1.8.3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/28/v1.8.3.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;183---2020-04-28&quot;&gt;1.8.3 - 2020-04-28&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning:&lt;/em&gt; This update modifies how information is stored in Elasticsearch for text based searching. To take advantage 
of these changes a reindex of Elasticsearch is required. This can be started by an admin either from GUI or through the API.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elasticsearch indexer will now store new metadata fields as strings to avoid unexpected behavior on date fields.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When reindexing use a temporary index to reindex while the current one is in use then swap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fixed&quot;&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to delete tags from sections and files on the file page. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1046&quot;&gt;CATS-1046&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1042&quot;&gt;CATS-1042&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User-owned resources will now appear in search results regardless of space permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating space ownership for datasets and collections will correctly reindex those resources for searches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Missing index in statistics which would slow down system when inserting download/views.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GitHub Actions to compile and test the code base, create documentation and docker images.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code of Conduct as MD file (will be displayed by GitHub).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Templates for Bug, Feature and Pull Request on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luigi Marini</name></author><summary type="html">1.8.3 - 2020-04-28 Warning: This update modifies how information is stored in Elasticsearch for text based searching. To take advantage of these changes a reindex of Elasticsearch is required. This can be started by an admin either from GUI or through the API.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">v1.8.2 Released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/v1.8.2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="v1.8.2 Released" /><published>2020-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/v1.8.2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/19/v1.8.2.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;182---2020-02-19&quot;&gt;1.8.2 - 2020-02-19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fixed&quot;&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the passed-in length within S3ByteStorageService.save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luigi Marini</name></author><summary type="html">1.8.2 - 2020-02-19</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">v1.8.1 Released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/05/v1.8.1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="v1.8.1 Released" /><published>2020-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/02/05/v1.8.1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/02/05/v1.8.1.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;181---2020-02-05&quot;&gt;1.8.1 - 2020-02-05&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;removed&quot;&gt;Removed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed unused RDF libraries. This was probably used by the rdf/xml functionality that was removed a while back but 
the dependencies were never removed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed Jena validation of JSON-LD metadata. It was creating a blank graph and clients couldn’t upload metadata when 
Clowder runs in a location that doesn’t not have access to https://clowderframework.org/contexts/metadata.jsonld.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scripts to migrate files on disk AWS S3.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1034&quot;&gt;CATS-1034&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include collection prefix in path when saving to S3.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include length of file in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FileService&lt;/code&gt; when saving the bytes to any backend service. This helps optimize S3 implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upgraded sbt from 0.13.0 to 0.13.6 to fix build failures.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1038&quot;&gt;CATS-1038&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luigi Marini</name></author><summary type="html">1.8.1 - 2020-02-05</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">v1.8 Released</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/06/v1.8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="v1.8 Released" /><published>2019-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/11/06/v1.8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/11/06/v1.8.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;180---2019-11-06&quot;&gt;1.8.0 - 2019-11-06&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning:&lt;/em&gt; This update adds a new permission for archiving files and adds it to the Admin role. Please make sure
to run Clowder with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONGOUPDATE&lt;/code&gt; flag set to update the database.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;changed&quot;&gt;Changed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/api/search&lt;/code&gt; endpoint now returns JSON objects describing each result rather than just the ID. This endpoint has three
new parameters - from, size, and page. The result JSON objects will also return pagination data such as next and 
previous page if Elasticsearch plugin is enabled and these parameters are used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S3ByteStorageService now uses AWS TransferManager for saving bytes - uploads larger than ~1GB should now save more reliably.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/api/search&lt;/code&gt; endpoint now returns JSON objects describing each result rather than just the ID.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clean up docker build. Use new buildkit to speed up builds. Store version/branch/git as environment variables in 
docker image so that they can be inspected at runtime with Docker.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extractors are now in their own docker-compose file. Use Traefik for proxy. Use env file for setting options.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utilize bulk get methods for resources widely across the application, including checking permissions for many resources
at once. Several instances where checks for resource existence were being done multiple times (e.g. in a method and then
in another method the first one calls) to reduce MongoDB query load. These bulk requests will also report any missing
IDs in the requested list so developers can handle those appropriately if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Removed mini icons for resource types on tiles.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1031&quot;&gt;CATS-1031&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaned up pages to list and enable extractors. Added description of what the page does. Added links to extraction info 
pages. Removed authors from table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;added&quot;&gt;Added&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to pass runtime parameters to an extractor, with a UI form dynamically generated UI from extractor_info.json.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1019&quot;&gt;CATS-1019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infinite scrolling on search return pages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trigger archival process automatically based on when a file was last viewed/downloaded and the size of the file.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Script to check if mongodb/rabbitmq is up and running, used by Kubernetes Helm chart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Queuing system that allows services such as Elasticsearch and RabbitMQ to store requested actions in MongoDB
for handling asynchronously, allowing API calls to return as soon as the action is queued rather than waiting for
the action to complete.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New extractors monitor docker image to monitor extraction queues. Monitor app includes UI that shows selected 
information about the extractors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/api/thumbnails/:id&lt;/code&gt; endpoint to download a thumbnail image from ID found in search results.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New utility methods in services to retrieve multiple MongoDB resources in one query instead of iterating over a list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for MongoDB 3.6 and below. This required the removal of aggregators which can result in
operations taking a little longer. This is needed to support Clowder as a Kubernetes Helm chart.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-806&quot;&gt;CATS-806&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Tree view as a tab in home page to navigate resources as a hiearchical tree (spaces, collections, datasets, 
folders and files). The tree is lazily loaded using a new endpoint &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;api/tree/getChildrenOfNode&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fixed&quot;&gt;Fixed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Downloading metrics reports would fail due to timeout on large databases. Report CSVs are now streamed
to the client as they are generated instead of being generated on the server and sent at the end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social accounts would not properly be added to a space after accepting an email invite to join it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where extractors monitor will not print error, but just return 0 if queue is not found.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pagination controls are now vertically aligned and use unescaped ampersands.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changing the page size on dataset, collection, space listings would not properly update elements visible on the page.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1030&quot;&gt;CATS-1030&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added a max of 100 status messages on the  page listing all extractions. Before this trying to list all extractions in 
the system was causing the JVM to run out of memory.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.ncsa.illinois.edu/jira/browse/CATS-1032&quot;&gt;CATS-1032&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added padding to the top of the footer so that the superadmin notification does not cover buttons and the buttons
at the end of forms are not too close to the footer and difficult to see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Luigi Marini</name></author><summary type="html">1.8.0 - 2019-11-06 Warning: This update adds a new permission for archiving files and adds it to the Admin role. Please make sure to run Clowder with the MONGOUPDATE flag set to update the database.</summary></entry></feed>